Guide to the Crossing Borders, Bridging Generations oral history collection 2011.019
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Rajiv Miller, 2014 May 16; 2011.019.092
  In the interview, Miller discusses his Indian heritage; academic performance and behavior in elementary school; participation in afterschool clubs and sports; and romantic relationships. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Rajiv Miller's cousin, Hansraj Maharawal, 2011.019.034.; oral history with Rajiv Miller's cousin, Manissa Maharawal, 2011.019.093.; oral history with Rajiv Miller's sister, Neela Miller, 2011.019.079.
  East Indian Americans |z New Jersey |z Norwood; Education |z New Jersey; Norwood (N.J.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Student life and customs |z New Jersey |z Norwood; Sunset Park (New York, N.Y.)
- Janise Mitchell, 2014 February 21; 2011.019.075
  Janise Mitchell was born to African American parents in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Mitchell majored in communications and minored in theater at Temple University in Philadelphia. She lived in Brooklyn, New York and worked as a social studies teacher.
  In the interview, Mitchell discusses her childhood in Philadelphia; courtship and marriage to her husband; their experiences as an interracial couple; and raising their children in Brooklyn, New York during the 1980s. Interview conducted by Jeanmarie Theobalds.
  Oral history with Janise Mitchell's daughter, Jasmine Mitchell, 2011.019.055.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; African Americans |z Pennsylvania |z Philadelphia; Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Interpersonal racism; Interracial marriage; Parenthood; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Philadelphia (Pa.); Racially mixed families
- Jasmine Mitchell, 2013 August 19; 2011.019.055
  Jasmine Mitchell was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania and raised in Brooklyn, New York. Mitchell earned a B.A. in American studies from Williams College in Williamstown, Massachusetts and a Ph.D. in American studies from the University of Minnesota: Twin Cities. She worked as an assistant professor at the State University of New York at Old Westbury.
  In the interview, Mitchell discusses her family; racially ambiguous appearance; experiences of racism and stereotyping; marriage to her white American husband; childhood the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; and perceptions of crime, race, diversity and gentrification in Brooklyn, New York. Interview conducted by Jeanmarie Theobalds.
  Oral history with Jasmine Mitchell's mother, Janise Mitchell, 2011.019.075.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Bullying in schools |z New York (State) |z New York; Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Gaslight gazette, the Park Slope neighborhood guide; Gentrification |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Parenthood; Philadelphia (Pa.); Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Racism in education
- Amanda Claire Morales, 2013 January 26; 2011.019.045
  Amanda Claire Morales was born to a white American mother and a Puerto Rican father and raised in the Fresh Meadows neighborhood of Queens. Morales received a B.A. in philosophy and art from the College of William and Mary in Williamsburg, Virginia. She lived in the Williamsburg, Greenpoint, and Park Slope neighborhoods of Brooklyn.
  In the interview, Morales discusses her childhood; Puerto Rican heritage; educational experiences in New York City public schools; impressions of the academic philosophy of the College of William and Mary; and participation in campus dialogues about race and racism. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z Virginia; Fresh Meadows (New York, N.Y.); Greenpoint (New York, N.Y.); Interracial dating; Puerto Ricans |z New York (State) |z New York; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Williamsburg (New York, N.Y.)
- Mala Yee Mosher and Sham Yee Mosher, 2013 March 8; 2011.019.025
  Mala Yee Mosher was born to a Burmese mother and a Malaysian Chinese father and raised in New York City. Mala attended the United Nations International School in New York City and Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island. She lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked in the theater industry as a stage manager and company manager.
  Sham Yee Mosher was born to an African American mother and a white American father in Washington, D.C. He was raised in an American Sikh community and attended boarding school in India for three years. Sham attended Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island. He lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as an artist and art teacher.
  In the interview, Mala and Sham discuss their courtship and marriage; racial and ethnic identities; encounters with racism; and aspirations for their children. Sham discusses his experience growing up in a primarily white Sikh community. Mala discusses her experiences at the United Nations International School in New York City and traveling in Burma. Interview conducted by Angela Tucker.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Burmese |z New York (State) |z New York; Cultural assimilation; Education, Higher |z Rhode Island |z Providence; Ethnic identity; Interethnic marriage; Interfaith dating; Interracial dating; Racial stereotyping; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Sikh Americans; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Yasmin Nagi, 2014 March 18; 2011.019.082
  Yasmin Nagi was born to a Sudanese mother and a Yemeni father in Brooklyn, New York. She was raised in Sana'a, Yemen and Brooklyn. Nagi studied international relations at the City College of New York in Manhattan, New York and served as a volunteer and youth fellow with the Arab Association of New York.
  In the interview, Nagi discusses navigating her identity as an Arab American in New York City and Yemen; gender roles and cultural differences in Yemen, Sudan, and New York City; and her parents' courtship, marriage, and decision to leave Yemen. Interview conducted by Amna Ahmad.
  Arab Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Bay Ridge (New York, N.Y); Cultural assimilation; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Hijab (Islamic clothing) |z United States; Interethnic marriage; Islamophobia; Muslims |z New York (State) |z New York; Sana'a (Yemen); Sex role
- Alicia Ohs, 2014 June 6; 2011.019.100
  Alicia Ohs was born to a Japanese American mother and a white American father on a United States Air Force base outside of Landstahl, Germany. She was raised in Marina and Lancaster, California. Ohs attended New York University in New York City and worked as a dancer, teaching artist, and yoga instructor in San Francisco, California and New York City.
  In the interview, Ohs discusses her racial and sexual identities; Japanese and American ancestry; parents' marriage and Christian convictions; maternal grandparents' experiences in a Japanese internment camp during World War II; involvement in theatre communities in New York City and San Francisco; experience during September 11 terrorist attacks; and an experience of an arrest in New York City. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
  Arrest |z New York (State) |z New York; Buddhism; Christianity; Japanese Americans |x Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Queer identity; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; San Francisco (Calif.); September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001; Sex role
- Alece Oxendine, 2014 May 2; 2011.019.085
  Alece Oxendine was born to African American parents in Greensboro, North Carolina and raised in Durham, North Carolina. Oxendine received a B.A. in English and mass communications from Winston-Salem State University in North Carolina and an M.A. in film studies from Columbia University in New York City. She worked in the film industry in New York City.
  In the interview, Oxendine discusses her racial identity; Native American heritage; encounters with racism; educational experiences; impressions of race and class divisions in her high school, college, and graduate school; parents’ courtship and marriage; and work on independent films. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; African Americans |z North Carolina |z Durham; Cultural diversity; Durham (N.C.); Education |z North Carolina |z Durham; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Independent films; Lumbee Indians |z North Carolina; Race identity; Racially mixed people; Racism in education |z North Carolina |z Durham
- Alicia Piller, 2012 February 8; 2012 April 12; 2011.019.016.027
  Alicia Piller was born to an African American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Chicago, Illinois. Piller attended Rutgers University in New Brunswick, New Jersey and worked as an artist and jewelry designer in Brooklyn, New York.
  In the interviews, Piller discusses her childhood in Chicago; racial and religious identities; romantic relationships and sexuality; parents’ courtship and marriage; family’s spiritual beliefs and religious traditions; visits to Tanzania with her father; and impressions of living in Brooklyn, New York. Interviews conducted by Sady Sullivan.
  Oral history with Alicia Piller's partner, Justice Whitaker, 2011.019.028.
  African American Jews |z Illinois |z Chicago; African Americans |z Illinois |z Chicago; Artists |z New York (State) |z New York; Chicago (Ill.); Homophobia; Interfaith families; Jews, American |z Illinois |z Chicago; Kilimanjaro, Mount (Tanzania); Queer identity; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Religious identity
- Emily Pinkowitz, 2012 November 12; 2011.019.039
  Emily Pinkowitz was born to a mixed race American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. Pinkowitz received a B.A. from Pomona College in Claremont, California and an M.A. in museum studies from New York University in New York City. She worked for the Lower East Side Tenement Museum and Friends of the High Line, both cultural institutions in New York City.
  In the interview, Pinkowitz discusses her racially ambiguous appearance; mother's Chinese and American heritage; family’s Jewish traditions; childhood friendships; experiences at the Hunter College Campus Schools in New York City; and romantic relationships. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Emily Pinkowitz's mother, Janet Pinkowitz, 2011.019.067.; Oral history with Emily Pinkowitz's partner, Ari Joseph, 2011.019.033.
  Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York; Chinese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Interfaith families; Interracial dating; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Judaism; Passing (Identity); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Janet Pinkowitz, 2013 October 29; 2011.019.067
  Janet Pinkowitz was born to a Chinese mother and a white American father in Chongqing, China. She was raised in Canton, China and Springfield, Massachusetts. Pinkowitz studied music at Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts and worked as a librarian.
  In the interview, Pinkowitz discusses her family history; Chinese heritage; and marriage to a Jewish American man and their children; impressions of communism in China; cultural preservation in the United States; and passing privilege. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Oral history with Janet Pinkowitz's daughter, Emily Pinkowitz, 2011.019.039.
  Chinese Americans |z Massachusetts; Chinese |z Massachusetts |z Springfield; Communism |z China; Guangzhou (China); Interfaith families; Massachusetts; Passing (Identity); Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people
- Conor Tomas Reed, 2014 June 4; 2011.019.102
  Conor Tomas Reed was born to a Puerto Rican mother and an Irish American father in Baltimore, Maryland and raised in New York City and Texas. Reed attended the City College of New York and studied English at the Graduate Center at City University of New York, both located in New York City. He was actively involved in the Occupy Wall Street movement.
  In the interview, Reed discusses his racial identity; educational experiences; parents’ activism with the nuclear disarmament movement; and his own activism, particularly with the Occupy Wall Street movement. Interview conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Demonstrations |z United States; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Occupy movement |z New York (State) |z New York; Police brutality |z United States; Puerto Ricans |z Texas; Race identity; Racially ambiguous people; Racially mixed families
- Anna Roberts, 2013 June 11; 2011.019.056
  Anna Roberts was born to a white American mother and an African American father in upstate New York. Roberts received a B.A. in sociology and history from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts. She worked at the Relay Graduate School of Education and the Institute of International Education, both located in New York City.
  In the interview, Roberts discusses her interest in sociology and education; experiences attending public and private schools; relationships with siblings; parents' courtship and marriage; and relatives' interracial relationships. Interview conducted by Alexandra Kelly.
  Education |z Northeastern States; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Northampton; Larchmont (N.Y.); Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.); Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Student life and customs |z Northeastern States
- Manu Sachdeva and Laurel Turbin, 2012 December 3; 2011.019.041
  Manu Sachdeva was born to Punjabi parents in Amritsar, India. Sachdeva's family immigrated to the United States when he was seven years old. He was raised in Vermont and received a B.F.A. in visual communication design from the University of Hartford in Connecticut. He worked as a graphic and web designer in New York City, Oakland, California, and Oahu, Hawaii.
  Laurel Turbin was born to a Chinese American mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in Honolulu, Hawaii. Turbin attended the University of California at Los Angeles and received an M.P.H. from Columbia University in New York City. She went on to pursue a Ph.D. in geography at the Graduate Center at City University of New York.
  In the interviews, Turbin and Sachdeva discuss their gender, racial, and queer identities; families’ Jewish and Sikh religious convictions; involvement in the Asian American community in New York City; and plans for having children. Interviews conducted by Manissa Maharawal.
  Asian American Jews |z Hawaii |z Honolulu; Chinese Americans |z Hawaii |z Honolulu; East Indian Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z New York; Gender identity; Interfaith dating; Interracial dating; Queer identity; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Sikh Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Christy Sacks and Stephen Sacks, 2013 October 12; 2013 October 13; 2011.019.066
  Christy Sacks was born to white American Episcopalian parents in Lancaster, Pennsylvania and raised in Port Washington, New York. Christy received a B.A. in English from Cornell University in Ithaca, New York and an M.A. in English from the University of California in Berkeley. She worked a high school teacher, social worker, and computer programmer.
  Stephen Sacks was born to white American Jewish parents and raised in Boston, Massachusetts. Stephen received a B.A. in economics from Harvard University in Cambridge, Massachusetts, a graduate degree in economics from the London School of Economics in England, and a Ph.D. in economics from the University of California at Berkeley. He worked as a professor of economics at the University of Connecticut in Storrs.
  In the interviews, Christy and Stephen Sacks discuss their childhoods; career paths; courtship and interfaith marriage; and move to Brooklyn, New York. They also discuss Christy's English ancestry; Stephen's Russian Jewish ancestry; and raising their two children in Storrs, Connecticut. Interviews conducted by Abigail Ettelman.
  Boston (Mass.); Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.); Episcopalians |z New York (State) |z Port Washington; Hebrew language; Interfaith families; Interfaith marriage; Jews, American |z Massachusetts |z Boston; Judaism; Port Washington (N.Y.); Religious identity; Storrs (Conn.)
- Harry Schwartzman, 2011 December 15; 2011.019.006
  Harry Schwartzman was born to a Japanese mother and a white American Jewish father and raised in New York City. He received an undergraduate degree from McGill University in Montreal, Canada and worked at the Lower East Side Tenement Museum in New York City.
  In the interview, Schwartzman discusses his childhood in the Upper East Side neighborhood of Manhattan; cultural and linguistic heritage; experiences as a Japanese, Yiddish and English speaker; and impressions of racial and ethnic diversity in New York City, Japan, and Canada. Interview conducted by Becky Amato.
  Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z New York; Cultural diversity; Japan; Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration; Upper East Side (New York, N.Y.)
- Stephanie Skaff, 2011 December 8; 2011.019.003
  Stephanie Skaff was born to parents with Lebanese, Polish, Irish, and German heritage and raised in Perrysburg, Ohio. Skaff lived in New York City and worked as an artist and activist on anti-gun violence campaigns.
  In the interview, Skaff discusses her ethnic identity; Lebanese heritage; experiences with racism and racial profiling in Brooklyn, New York; parents' marriage and divorce; relatives' perceptions of race; and travel experiences in Morocco. Interview conducted by Katrina Grigg-Saito.
  Clinton Hill (New York, N.Y.); Crime |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Ethnic identity; Interethnic marriage; Lebanese Americans |z Ohio |z Perysburg; Morocco; Perrysburg (Ohio); Racial stereotyping |z New York (State) |z Kings County
- Shawnta Smith, 2012 June 10; 2011.019.035
  Shawnta Smith was born to a Belizean American mother and a Jamaican father and raised in the East Flatbush and Brownsville neighborhoods of Brooklyn. Smith received a B.S. in queer women's studies from the City University of New York, and an M.L.S. and M.F.A. in fiction from Queens College, all located in New York City. She worked as an archivist at the Lesbian Herstory Archives and as reference librarian at the City University of New York.
  In the interview, Smith discusses her childhood and adolescence years in Brooklyn, New York; sexual identity; experiences as a queer activist; father's music and involvement in Rastafarianism; parents' divorce; and incidents of child abuse in her family. Interview conducted by Svetlana Kitto.
  African Americans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Brownsville (New York, N.Y.); Community activists |z New York (State) |z New York; East Flatbush (New York, N.Y.); Education |z New York (State) |z New York; Family violence; Gangs |z New York (State) |z Kings Country; Jamaicans |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Queer identity
- Lara Stapleton, 2014 May 23; 2011.019.090
  Lara Stapleton was born to a Filipino mother and a white American father and raised in East Lansing, Michigan. Stapleton received her undergraduate degree from Michigan State University and an M.A. in creative writing from New York University in New York City. She worked as a writer and lecturer in the English Department at the Borough of Manhattan Community College in New York City.
  In the interview, Stapleton discusses her parents' courtship and marriage; mother's immigration to the United States from Manila, Philippines; childhood in Michigan; racial identity; educational experiences; and creative writing. Interview conducted by Jennifer Scott.
  Education, Higher |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Filipino Americans |z Michigan; Fort Greene (New York, N.Y.); Manila (Philippines); Michigan; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration; World War, 1939-1945 |z Philippines |z Manila
- Asha Sundararaman, 2012 January 8; 2011.019.010
  Asha Sundararaman was born to a white American mother and an Indian father in Palo Alto, California. She was raised in California, Indiana, Canada, and Nigeria. Sundararaman received a B.A. in Africana studies and theatre studies from Wellesley College in Massachusetts and an M.A. in international studies and diplomacy from the University of London in England. Sundararaman lived in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as the volunteer coordinator for Orbis International, a nonprofit organization dedicated to preventing and treating blindness in developing countries.
  In the interview, Sundararaman discusses her racial and cultural identities; family’s frequent relocations; involvement in Fusion, an organization for mixed race students at Wellesley College; impressions of race and community dynamics in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn; and work for Orbis International. Interview conducted by Jen Chau.
  East Indian Americans; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Wellesley; Indiana; Interfaith families; Nigeria; Park Slope (New York, N.Y.); Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; United States |x Emigration and immigration
- Sonnet Takahisa, 2012 January 31; 2011.019.015
  Sonnet Takahisa was born to an American Jewish mother and a Japanese American father and raised in Brooklyn, New York. She received a B.A. in East Asian studies from Harvard University in Boston, Massachusetts and an M.A. in East Asian and Japanese studies from the University of Washington at Seattle. She worked as the director of education at the National September 11 Memorial & Museum in New York City.
  In the interview, Takahisa discusses her parents' views on atheism and Zionism; paternal grandfather's immigration to the United States; career path; and practice of honoring Japanese holidays and traditions. Interview conducted by Elisabeth Pozzi-Thanner.
  Asian American Jews |z New York (State) |z Kings County; Education, Higher |z Massachusetts |z Boston; Japan; Japanese Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Jews, Americans |z New York (State) |z New York; Museums |z New York (State) | New York; Parenthood; Race identity; Racially mixed families; Racially mixed people; Seattle (Wa.)
- Leila Tamari, 2014 February 23; 2011.019.078
  Leila Tamari was born in New York City to a Haitian mother and a French Jewish father in New York City. Tamari received a B.A. in art history from Smith College in Northampton, Massachusetts. She lived in the Crown Heights neighborhood of Brooklyn and worked as a programming coordinator at Creative Time, a public arts organization in New York City.
  In the interview, Tamari discusses her ethnic and racial identities; experiences with interracial dating; parents' courtship, marriage, and relationships with extended family members; father's cultural and religious identities; mother's immigration to the United States from Haiti; and impressions of gentrification in New York City. Interview conducted by Kendra Danowski.